strive.ai 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy – strive.ai

Your privacy is very important to us. Please read below to see how Strive.ai handles information. Before you get to the details, here are a few of our fundamental privacy principles:

  * Your privacy is critically important to us and we handle your information accordingly.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone without your consent except to comply with the law, develop our products and services, or protect our rights.
  * Information you upload or post to Strava and/or Strive.ai may be seen by others depending on your privacy settings.
  * We aggregate and de-identify information about our members to use for business purposes.
  * We give you several ways to control the privacy of your personal information and are continuously working to enhance privacy options available to you.

Strive.ai respects your privacy and shares your concern about the security of data you may submit to Strive.ai’s websites and the related mobile applications and services (collectively, the “Services”). Our privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) explains the information we collect, how we use and protect it, how to access and update your information, and how to manage your privacy settings when using the Services. This policy was written in English. To the extent a translated version conflicts with the English version, the English version controls.

Questions or comments about this Privacy Policy may be submitted by mail to the address below or via [bot@strive.ai](mailto:bot@strive.ai?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

**strive.ai**  
279 Claudia Ct  
Moraga, CA 94556  
Attn: Legal

**Information Strive.ai Collects**

Strive.ai collects information about you, including personally identifiable information, if you choose to share it with Strava or Strive.ai, register an account, or if you track, complete or upload activities using the Services. Strive.ai also collects information about how you use the Services. There are several opportunities for you to share information about yourself and your activities with Strive.ai, including your name, physical address, email address, gender, age, equipment usage, activities, routes (including date, time and geo-location information as well as your speed and pace), profile photo and other pictures. You may also submit other content to be shared.

If you elect to use location-based features via the Services, then the physical location of your device will be collected. Strive.ai may also collect and upload from your device data such as speed and direction. You are able to disallow our use of certain location data through your device or browser settings by disabling “Location Services”.

Strava allows you to sign up and log in to the Services using accounts you create with third-party products and services, such as Facebook or Google (collectively, “Third-Party Accounts”). These Third-Party Accounts may ask your permission to share certain information from your Third-Party Account with Strive.ai. We use this information to verify your identity as well as to provide you with features of our products and services. This information may include your first and last name, email address, profile information and preferences with the applicable Third-Party Account. This information is collected by the Third-Party Account provider and is provided to Strive.ai under their privacy policies. You can generally control the information that we receive from these sources using the privacy settings in your Third-Party Account. You can deactivate your account at any time by visiting _[Strava Apps Settings](https://www.strava.com/settings/apps)_.

**How Information is Collected and Stored**

Strive.ai collects information you provide to us. When you register, and agree to our Terms of Service, you must provide personal information such as your name and email address. You may also upload location-based activities, such as a run or a ride, to the Services. You may join challenges, contests, post photos and communicate with other members. You may also provide additional personal information or payment information to complete your member profile or make purchases.

Strive.ai also automatically collects a variety of technical information, including location, device and network information, cookies, log files and analytics services.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

When you visit the Services, a cookie will be stored on your computer. Generally, cookies and similar work by assigning to your computer a unique number that has no meaning outside of Strive.ai. Strive.ai’s cookies do not contain any personally identifying information; Strive.ai uses them to personalize your experience. Strive.ai may also use cookies to assist it in delivering content specific to your interests. Additionally, after you’ve entered your member ID and password during a session on the Services, Strive.ai saves that information so you don’t have to re-enter it repeatedly during that session. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. The only way to “opt out” of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser or mobile device. Please refer to your browser’s or mobile device’s technical information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools. If you have any questions about opting out of the collection of cookies and other tracking/recording tools, please contact us. Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the Services unavailable to you. Strive.ai may also use your IP address to identify you, to administer the Services and to assist in diagnosing problems with Strive.ai’s servers.

**Log Files**

The Services uses log files. Stored information includes IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the Services, track member movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc., may be linked to session IDs, athlete IDs and device identifiers.

**Analytics Services**

Strive.ai may use third party analytics providers to understand how the Services are used and to help us improve the Services.

**Collection from Children**

Strive.ai is not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Strive.ai does not knowingly collect such information. If you believe we may have accidentally received such information, please contact us immediately via _[bot@strive.ai](mailto:bot@strive.ai?subject=Children%20Under%2013)_.

**Third Parties**

Strive.ai may collect personally identifiable information about your activities over time and across third-party websites or online services when you use the Services. We may obtain additional information about you from third parties such as marketers, partners, researchers, and others. We may combine information that we collect from you with information obtained from such third parties and information derived from any other subscription, product, or service we provide.

Strive.ai is committed to providing you choices to manage your privacy and sharing. However, Strive.ai does not recognize or respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals, as the internet industry has not fully developed Do Not Track standards, implementations and solutions. To learn more about Do Not Track signals, you can visit [https://allaboutdnt.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

**How Strive.ai Uses Information**

Strive.ai primarily uses the information we collect to administer and operate the Services. We also use your information to analyze, develop and improve the Services. We may also use your information to market the services, credit or accept payments, provide support related to the Services, protect members and enforce our [Terms of Service](https://strive.ai/terms_of_service), promote safety, and communicate with you. Additionally, your information may be shared with third parties, as set forth below.

**How Information is Shared**

**Publicly Available Information**

Your personal performance metrics are only visible to you on the Services.  One exception to that guideline are the Segment Effort leaderboards.  For example, segment effort performance stack ranking is available for all segments completed by users with power meters.  This information is only available to authorized Service users.

**Third Party Business via API or Other Integrations**

When you use third party apps, plug-ins, or websites that integrate with the Services, they may receive your information and content, including your personal information, photos, and your activity data (including private activities). Information collected by these third parties is subject to their terms and policies. Strive.ai is not responsible for the terms or policies of third parties.

**Sharing within Strive.ai**

We may share your information and content within Strive.ai to operate, improve, or promote the Services.

**Service Providers**

We may share your information with third parties who provide services to Strive.ai such as supporting and improving the Services, promoting the Services, processing payments, or fulfilling orders. These service providers will only have access to the information necessary to perform these limited functions on our behalf and are required to protect and secure your information. We may also service providers to collect information about your use of the Services over time so that we or they may promote Strive.ai or display information that may be relevant to your interests on the Services or other websites or services.

**Affiliates and Acquirers of our Business or Assets**

We may share your information with affiliates under common control with us, who are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy with regard to your information. If Strive.ai becomes involved in a business combination, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution or other similar transaction, we may share or transfer your information in connection with such transaction.

**Aggregated and De-Identified Information**

Strive.ai may modify, de-identify and aggregate the information, data, text, software, sound, photographs, graphics, video, messages, tags, or other materials you make available in connection with the Services (“Content”), in ways that do not personally identify you or contain personally identifiable information. Examples of such aggregated information or statistical data include information about equipment and usage, demographic and route information and performance or biometric information. Strive.ai may use, sell, license, and share this information with third parties for research, business or other purposes. If you make information or content publicly available on the Services, such information, even when aggregated, is capable of being publicly viewed and possibly associated with you.

**With Consent**

We may share your information if (i) you direct us to do so or (ii) you otherwise consent to such sharing.

**Legal Requirements**

We may share your information with third parties, including law enforcement, public or governmental agencies, or private litigants, within or outside your country of residence, if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with the law, including to respond to court orders, warrants, subpoenas, or other legal or regulatory process. We may also disclose your information if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary or appropriate to prevent any person from death or serious bodily injury, to address issues of national security or other issues of public importance, to prevent or detect violations of our [Terms of Service](https://strive.ai/terms_of_service) or fraud or abuse of Strive.ai or its members, or to protect our operations or our property or other legal rights, including by disclosure to our legal counsel and other consultants and third parties in connection with actual or potential litigation.

**DMCA Notices**

We may share your information with third parties when we forward Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DCMA) notifications, which will be forwarded as submitted to us without any deletions.

**Unforeseeable Disclosures**

Your personally identifiable information may be disclosed to third parties in unforeseeable situations that are not preventable even when commercially reasonable protections are employed, such as in the case that Strive.ai or the Services is subject to a hacking or other attack.

**How We Protect Information**

We take several measures to safeguard the collection, transmission and storage of the data we collect. These steps depend on the sensitivity of the data that we collect, process, and store. Although we strive to employ reasonable protections for your information that are appropriate to its sensitivity, we do not guarantee or warrant the security of the information you share with us and we are not responsible for the theft, destruction, loss or inadvertent disclosure of your information or content. No system is 100% secure. The Services uses industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to allow for the encryption of personal information and credit card numbers. Strive.ai engages a company that is an industry leader in online security and Services verification to strengthen the security of Strive.ai’s Services. The Services are registered with site identification authorities so that your browser can confirm Strive.ai’s identity before any personally identifiable information is sent. In addition, Strive.ai’s secure servers protect this information using advanced firewall technology.

To help ensure that these measures are effective in preventing unauthorized access to your private information, you should be aware of the security features available to you through your browser. You should use a security-enabled browser to submit your credit card information and other personal information at the Services. Please note that if you do not use a SSL-capable browser, you are at risk for having data intercepted.

Most browsers have the ability to notify you if you change between secure and insecure communications, receive invalid Services identification information for the Services you are communicating with, or send information over an unsecured connection. Strive.ai recommends that you enable these browser functions to help ensure that your communications are secure. You can also monitor the URL of the Services you are visiting (secure URLs begin with https:// rather than http://), along with the security symbol of your browser to help identify when you are communicating with a secure server. You can also view the details of the security certificate of the Services to which you are connected. Please check the validity of any Services you connect to using secure communications.

**How to Opt Out or Adjust Notification and Email Preferences**

We offer various ways to opt-out or opt-into our notifications, located at <https://beta.strive.ai/settings/>. To choose to stop receiving certain emails from Strive.ai, please follow the unsubscribe instructions within each email communication or contact us at [bot@strive.ai](mailto:bot@strive.ai?subject=Unsubscribe). Strive.ai will not provide or share any mailing lists or other information about you to another company or service other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Any administrative or service related emails (to confirm a purchase, or an update to the [Terms of Service](https://strava.com/legal/terms), etc.) generally do not offer an option to unsubscribe as they are necessary to provide the service you requested.

**Updating Account Information**

You may correct, amend or delete submitted account information that is inaccurate at any time by adjusting that information in your account settings. If you need further assistance, please contact Strive.ai at [bot@strive.ai](mailto:bot@strive.ai?subject=Updating%20User%20Content). Strive.ai will generally respond to your request within 7-10 business days.

**Deleting Information and Deactivation of Accounts**

You may request deletion of your personally identifiable information by contacting us at [bot@strive.ai](mailto:bot@strive.ai?subject=Delete%20User%20Data) to request account deletion. Once deactivated, your account, activities and place on leaderboards cannot be reinstated.

Note that content you have shared with others (for example, through Clubs) or that others have copied may also remain visible after you have closed your account or deleted the information from your own profile. In addition, you may not be able to access, correct, or eliminate any information about you that other members or third parties copied or exported out of our Services. Your public profile may be displayed in search engine results until the search engine refreshes its cache.

**Other Strive.ai Sites**

Strive.ai maintains certain websites that can be accessed outside of [https://beta.strive.ai](https://beta.strive.ai/), such as [https://strive.ai](https://strive.ai/) (the “Other Sites”). The Other Sites maintain the look and feel of the Services, but are hosted by outside service providers with their own terms and privacy policies. If you interact with the Other Sites, your information may be stored, processed, or shared outside of the Services. If you interact with the Other Sites, you agree that you may be subject to the terms and conditions and policies applicable to such Other Site. Please be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit to the Other Sites may be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums indefinitely, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Strive.ai is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit via the Other Sites.

**Privacy Policy Information**

If Strive.ai makes changes to this Privacy Policy, the updated Privacy Policy will be posted on the Services in a timely manner. If the changes are significant, we will provide a prominent notice. Strive.ai reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If you object to any of the changes to Privacy Policy, you may cease using the Services and deactivate your account. Using the Services after a notice of changes has been communicated to you or published on the Services shall constitute your agreement to the changes.

**United States Operation**

The Services are operated from the United States. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Services or provide information to us, your information will be transferred, processed and stored in the United States. United States privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. You acknowledge and consent to this practice.

**Disclaimer**

While Strive.ai continues to work hard to protect your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure, and Strive.ai cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Strive.ai. Transmitting personal information is done at your own risk.

**Retention of Information**

We retain information as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. Information about you that is no longer necessary and relevant for our operations will be de-identified and/or disposed of securely. In addition, we may retain information from closed accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the Services’ terms and conditions and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

When you delete your user account, certain personal information will be immediately de-associated with the account and deleted, such as your e-mail, name, address, and profile photo, if you had chosen to provide this information. Additionally, your Third-Party Account information will be immediately de-associated with your account. All of your activities and kudos will be de-identified, made private and no longer associated with your personal information. Your comments will be deleted and your account will not be associated with any clubs you had previously joined. We may, however, keep a record of your deletion for up to 30 days following your deletion of an account. Additionally, we may keep system logs, which may be associated with your account for up to 30 days following your deletion of an account.

When you delete your account, we may retain geolocation information to continue to improve the Services. Upon deletion of your account, however, this information cannot be viewed by other users and will be de-associated with your name and other identifiers.
